<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title></title>
		<description></description>
		<link></link>
		
			<item>
				<title>What a year</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Ah it&#39;s been more two months since I last blogged. Life&#39;s been very busy the past three months and when I&#39;m busy, I kind of let the things I enjoy doing slip, so that&#39;s my excuse for not having blogged for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013 has been a huge year for me. It&#39;s been a very busy but great one. To summarise in order of occurence:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worked as a remote contractor and got to experience the freedom of working from home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got engaged&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did my first public speaking at Web Directions &quot;What Do You Know&quot; about &lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/mobywhale/how-to-create-a-living-style-guide&quot;&gt;how to create a living style guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got my own place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started up &lt;a href=&quot;http://sydcss.com&quot;&gt;SydCSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spoke at Web Directions Sotuh for the first time about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k1VOpxdoRIY&quot;&gt;how to avoid spaghetti code in your CSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got married&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It felt like everything was happening at once especially the last three months. It was stressful but  I&#39;m so glad the year has turned out the way it did. My biggest takeaway for the year? Confidence. Even though I only spoke publicly a grand total of 25 minutes in the entire year, it still gave me a lot more confidence than anything else I&#39;ve done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New year resolution for 2014? Continue to be happy, content, healthy and keep doing what I&#39;m passionate about. Also to cook Jamie Oliver&#39;s 15 minutes meal in 15 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<published>2013-12-30 00:00:00 +1100</published>
				<link>/2013/12/what-a-year.html</link>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>First SydCSS</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;M ON SUCH A HIGH RIGHT NOW! Seriously, I&#39;m buzzing. Not from an overdose of caffeine or sugar, but because THE FIRST NIGHT OF &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sydcss.com&quot;&gt;SYDCSS&lt;/a&gt; WAS A FRIGGING SUCCESS! I am just soooooo happy with how well it went. It&#39;s almost 12:30am now but I just want to capture everything about the night while it&#39;s still fresh in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why SydCSS?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love CSS (most of the time). And I love talking to people about CSS/front-end in general. A lot of people I follow on Twitter from the US and Europe would tweet about various CSS-related talks at different meetups. They always made me feel jealous and a little sad that we didn&#39;t have something similar here. I really wanted to have the same tight knit community they&#39;ve got, so I could share with people the new RWD technique I learnt, or whinge together about the difficulty of doing vertical alignment in this day and age. I just wanted to meet more people like me, so what better way to do that than to start a meetup group to bring everyone together! :) Lucky for me, my friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/dp_lewis&quot;&gt;David&lt;/a&gt; was keen on the idea as well and was more than happy to help put this together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The preparation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After organising the meetup, I have a new found respect for people who organise conferences. There was certainly a lot of work involved. We put our page up on meetup.com, thinking if anyone would actually want to join. But with the power of social media, words got out and we now have &gt; 150 members in 2 months time. I&#39;m not sure what the sign up rate is like normally, but I am more than happy with how well-received the group has been so far. We contacted the speakers we wanted to have on the first night, and both &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/russmaxdesign&quot;&gt;Russ Weakley&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/alexanderdanilo&quot;&gt;Alex Danilo&lt;/a&gt; agreed immediately to come and speak. We also went and got our own portable lectern, screen and projector. All for the love of the meetup group!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted the meetup to have a fun and relaxed feel, and make it a bit more different. Instead of pizza you&#39;d normally get at meetups, we decided to provide homemade popcorn on the first night! Well, in truth, it was also because we don&#39;t have a sponsor yet to help with the food :) I made about 3 pots worth of popcorn. There was A LOT of it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/photos/sydcss02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Popcorn!&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/photos/sydcss02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Popcorn!&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/photos/sydcss02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Popcorn!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;On the night&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I felt like a kid on Christmas Eve, waiting for Christmas to arrive at 6:30pm that night. I was nervous about MC&#39;ing for the first time, excited that it was finally happening and also worried that no one would turn up. To cut the story short, everything went extremely well. We held our first meetup at Web Directions office. It has a nice and relaxing feel about it so it was perfect. More people than expected turned up, both talks were engaging and informative, the popcorn went down well (yay!), no major technical issues (phew!)... It was just amazing. When I walked around during the break, people were mingling, chatting, laughing, and I could actually hear conversations about CSS. I thought to myself, &quot;Wow. People are actually here talking about it!&quot;. I&#39;m sorry I&#39;m not good at describing it better, but the whole night had such a great vibe and a lot of it had to do with the great audience we had. So big thank you to everyone who came last night!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MC&#39;ing for the first time with David. Eek!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/photos/sydcss01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MC&#39;ing for the first time&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David with our presenters&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/photos/sydcss03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;David with the presenters&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our happy audience!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/photos/sydcss04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;David with the presenters&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The first of many&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both David and I were so happy with how well it went. We really couldn&#39;t have asked for a better start. Feedbacks have all been positive so far and we are looking forward to making the next one even better. I also just want to give a shout-out to David for being such a great organiser. He thought of all the details I didn&#39;t think about and did a lot of the preparation. Thanks David!!! Really couldn&#39;t have done it without you :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Want to join? Or sponsor?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get notified about when our next meetup is going to be, go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://sydcss.com&quot;&gt;sydcss.com&lt;/a&gt;. And if you are interested in sposnoring this fun and friendly community, you can contact us at &lt;strong&gt;sydcssgroup at gmail dot com&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So... can we rewind the clock now and do SydCSS all over again tonight?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/photos/sydcss05.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Happy organisers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<published>2013-10-03 00:00:00 +1000</published>
				<link>/2013/10/first-sydcss.html</link>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Let's not forget the fundamentals</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Everyday on Twitter, I get swamped with tweets about new web technology, new techniques, how to build flashy layouts etc. While it&#39;s great that there are so many exciting things happening, I find that fundamentals like accessibility, performance and progressive enhancements often get forgotten and lost. In fact, they are things we should always be considering. Yes, to do a superb job in these areas can require a bit of work, but there are definitely a lot of simple things we can do to make a difference:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider semantics and use the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.karlgroves.com/2013/05/14/links-are-not-buttons-neither-are-divs-and-spans/&quot;&gt;correct HTML tags&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.paciellogroup.com/2013/02/using-wai-aria-landmarks-2013/&quot;&gt;ARIA landmark roles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider what content the screen readers will read out: will you need to hide content offscreen so what gets read out will make more sense to screen reader users?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a fallback for when JavaScript is disabled. Admittedly not all no-JavaScript fallback solutions are easy to implement, but simple things like ensuring content is displayed when JavaScript is disabled can be done quite easily&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider page weight especially if you have a lot of images. Even more so if you need to serve high-res images for retina screens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s keep pushing the web forward, but also let&#39;s not forget the fundamentals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related readings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jakearchibald.com/2013/progressive-enhancement-still-important/&quot;&gt;Progressive enhancement is still important&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://simplyaccessible.com/article/both/&quot;&gt;Design and Development: The Yin and Yang of Web Accessibility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gorkamolero.com/work/thought/Web-performance-2.html&quot;&gt;Web performance 2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
				<published>2013-09-24 00:00:00 +1000</published>
				<link>/2013/09/lets-not-forget-the-fundamentals.html</link>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>What I learnt about working remotely</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I left my full time job to take up an opportunity to work with &lt;a href=&quot;http://stubbornella.org&quot;&gt;Nicole Sullivan&lt;/a&gt;. She was based in San Francisco, I was in Sydney and the other developer on the team was in Paris. Yup, it was an international team!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;At the start&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first couple of months of working from home was awesome: worked in my pjs, worked at pretty much any hours that suited me, ran errands during the day which wouldn&#39;t have been possible if I worked in an office... in short, I had more freedom and control over what to do with my time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But after a while, I started to go a bit stir-crazy. I got lonely with no one to talk to face to face. When I hit a road block with work I couldn&#39;t just turn around to ask a question. I was struggling to focus as well. My productivity also dropped so I ended up sitting at my desk for 10 hours a day trying to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.reactiongifs.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Being-alone-sucks.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Lonely&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things got better over time, so I just want to share what have helped me to make the most of being a remote worker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Separate work and rest space&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People always say you should separate work and rest space. They are right. At the start I was working at a desk in my bedroom. I would literally roll out of bed and sit at my desk. I kept losing focus and procrastinated. And sometimes I would work till way past normal hours. It just wasn&#39;t working. So I tried to move to work in a different room, with a bit of skepticism whether it would actually work. After a while my mind would just immediately switch to work mode as soon as I sat down at the desk. And when I needed a break, I would just move to another room to stay away from my work space. I guess it&#39;s a psychological thing that you need that separate space, but seriously it works to keep your mind focused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Github&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Github is probably one of the biggest reasons why working remotely has worked. We used it within the team and with our clients to manage issues and code reviews. It became a central place for us to keep track of our discussions and decision making, rather than keeping things in emails that get lost in inboxes. And being able to do code reviews via pull requests have really allowed us to collaborate with the team remotely. &amp;lt;3 Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Go out and see people&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as I enjoy the quietness at home, it gets lonely. It&#39;s important to go out and see people regularly otherwise your mind can go a bit stir-crazy. Sometimes I&#39;ll work at &lt;a href=&quot;http://theworkben.ch/&quot;&gt;Workbench&lt;/a&gt;, a co-working space in Sydney. It&#39;s a great little space when I need to be around people and I&#39;ve met some great people through there. I also try to make good use of my freedom to meet with friends whom I won&#39;t normally get to have lunch with. Another thing that has helped me to stay connected is meetups. They are great for meeting likeminded people. I highly recommend anyone to go check out some of their local meetups if you haven&#39;t already. It&#39;s an excellent way to be involved in the community. Don&#39;t be shy if you don&#39;t know anyone at the meetups. People generally go to these things to mingle so it&#39;s perfectly ok to just walk up to strangers and introduce yourself :) (though to be honest, I still get shy when I go to these events)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Be independent and self-disciplined&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you work from home, it&#39;s so easy to just slack off. It really does require an extra level of self-disciplinary. I also found I had to be extra independent. Often when I worked, my colleagues were asleep due to time difference. So when I ran into problems, I could either wait 8 hours for them to wake up and help me (usually not the best option) or I really try to figure things out on my own. That means a lot of googling, and trial and error. A lot of the times I had to rely on my own judgement to decide the best solution. Sometimes it doesn&#39;t work, but you learn to make better choices the more practice you get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Be flexible&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s difficult to work with two time zones, let alone three! And that&#39;s what we had to deal with on our team. However we made it work, and that&#39;s largely because we were willing to be flexible with our availabilities. Whatever times we set for meetings, it would always be at an awkward time for one person: either very early, or very late. But we took turns so it wouldn&#39;t always be inconvenient for one person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working remotely (and from home) can have its downsides, but as long as you know how to work around them, the flexibility and freedom it provides is great :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<published>2013-08-21 00:00:00 +1000</published>
				<link>/2013/08/what-i-learnt-about-working-remotely.html</link>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Hello blog!</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Finally, I have my own blog setup. I&#39;ve always been a bit terrified about sharing my thoughts with the world. But after doing a couple of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stubbornella.org/content/2013/07/01/easy-peasy-rem-conversion-with-sass/&quot;&gt;short&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stubbornella.org/content/2013/07/31/re-visiting-the-secret-power-of-block-fomatting-context/&quot;&gt;blogposts&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8YtQwv1cUVs&quot;&gt;talks&lt;/a&gt;, I feel a bit more comfortable about the idea now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is still very much a work in progress, so bear with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some facts about this blog:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&#39;s powered by Jekyll, Sass and Compass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was going to call it &quot;Sprinkles&quot; because I liked the word. But then decided against it because I know my ever-changing mind will dislike it after a while&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time taken to choose the colour theme: 1 hour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time taken to choose the fonts: 4 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
				<published>2013-08-13 00:00:00 +1000</published>
				<link>/2013/08/hello-blog.html</link>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
